# MATT FITZPATRICK

T 314.680.1370 matt@50inthe314.com 50inthe314.com

Digital Marketing manager, specializing in brand management and promotions through content marketing and new media. Expertise in strategy and development, asset execution, and analysis of marketing campaigns. Able to develop unique marketing opportunities for brands/products while keeping the strategy and scope of the project in mind. Adapts well to changing targets, trends, and technology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### DIGITAL MARKETING MANAGER, SAINT LOUIS UNIVERSITY, ST. LOUIS, MO

JANUARY 2014 - PRESENT

- Lead digital marketing efforts, email, and social media campaigns for the John Cook School of Business.
- Implemented content marketing strategies and calendars. Organically increased audience 40% and reach 85%.
- Create/manage content for digital channels, including blogs, op-eds, press releases and photo/video content.
- Increased site traffic by 20% in 2014, with peak increases in social, email, and organic search traffic.
- Introduced social media to our digital marketing spend. Implemented Facebook and LinkedIn promoted posts, gained above average interactions and click-through-rate and tracked conversions for our MBA program.
- Manage multiple vendors/departments, work with both internal teams and outside agencies to expand efforts.
- Create and maintain digital standards and website, focus on Content Creation, SEO, and conversion analytics.

# ACCOUNT / MARKETING MANAGER, THE ABLE FEW, ST. LOUIS, MO NOVEMBER 2012 - NOVEMBER 2013

- Managed internal marketing for the firm, including B2B efforts, social media, and event planning.
- Worked in a continuous release cycle, where many hands were on a single project and concerted contact with the client was required to maintain the expected level of accuracy and excellence.
- Developed business plans, site maps, and feature release timelines for web applications that have been featured at South By Southwest, Mashable.com, and other technology events and publications.
- Expanded outreach and followed various paths to connect with new business, including creating responses to RFP's, creating formal proposals for new projects, and attending networking events and one-on-one meetings.

## ACCOUNT MANAGER, CTM MEDIA GROUP, ST. LOUIS, MO

OCTOBER 2011 - NOVEMBER 2012

- Managed over 400 traditional and digital advertising placements for an array of clients, from independent restaurants and stores to Fortune 500 companies, athletics and arenas, and major tourism attractions.
- Led expansion in the digital marketing realm, including growth of the brand on social media by over 100%, and introduced digital advertising tactics into traditional marketing techniques.
- Introduced a new hybrid marketing medium to the St. Louis area. Facilitated placement in high end hotels and premium attractions. Increased digital reach in the St. Louis area to 2.5 million visitors annually.
- Created and presented analytical reports and research studies for our clients, showing where their marketing plan succeeded and gave insight on how to improve when needed.

#### CONSUMER HOSPITALITY REP, ANHEUSER-BUSCH, ST. LOUIS, MO

SEPTEMBER 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2011

- Acted as brand ambassador for guests of Anheuser-Busch at the St. Louis Tour Center.
- Led tours of the brewery complex, educating visitors about the Anheuser-Busch brand and their portfolio.
- Coordinated projects among the staff, kept programs and day to day tasks running smoothly and efficiently.
- Promoted to Guest Service Specialist in fall of 2008.

## **PROFICIENCIES**

- Digital Marketing Salesforce, Email platforms (Mailchimp), Social media platforms (Hootsuite, Radian6).
- · Media Buying AdSense, AdWords, Social Media including Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Instagram.
- Media Production Expertise in Photoshop, Illustrator & InDesign, proficient in Final Cut Pro.
- Development Full Wordpress Builds, Read and Write CSS, PHP & Ruby, Operates well in most CMS's.
- Business Microsoft Office Suite, Basecamp and other project management software.

#### **EDUCATION**

WEBSTER UNIVERSITY - ST. LOUIS, MO
BA - ADVERTISING AND MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS
SAINT LOUIS UNIVERSITY - ST. LOUIS, MO
MBA - MARKETING

**GRADUATED WITH HONORS, MAY 2010** 

COMPLETION, 2017